It was an age of war.
Relying on only his own skill,
one man wandered the land.
A samurai.
This man is not
a wandering samurai of today.
Why did I ever enter
a restaurant like this?
I don't know what came over me.
GOOD FORTUNE
It looks like...
I made a huge mistake.
This... This is...
After retiring, he lost his title
as a corporate man
and the support of his company.
Takeshi Kasumi, 60 years old.
This story
is about a normal 60-year-old man
who is helped by a masterless samurai,
eating freely without being held back.
A gourmet fantasy.
Instead of lying around,
why don't you try starting a new hobby?
THE MADAM DEVIL
A new hobby? I'm not sure...
How about walking?
It'll be a good exercise.
All right.
Here I go.
Start!
As a company man,
all I thought about was work.
I never thought about hobbies.
Retirement is...
the start of a new life.
Okay.
I can't lose.
I used to be known as...
fleet-footed Kasumi.
I overdid it a bit.
Ouch.
I'm starting to get pretty hungry.
That's right.
I'll eat at that ramen shop.
They seem busy.
There's an empty seat.
Well then,
I'll have shoyu ramen today!
RAMEN NARITAKE
Welcome! Come in!
Beat me to it!
-Chashu ramen and gyoza, please.
-I don't want to wait.
I remember there's a ramen restaurant
on the next street over.
Wow.
GARLIC SHOYU RAMEN
SECOND FLOOR SEATS AVAILABLE
Hey, there's a line.
-Because it was on TV.
-Yes.
Why do Japanese people like lines so much?
Okay, we're going here.
Why would anyone wait so long
to eat ramen?
I don't get it.
Maybe so, but...
I feel like ramen now.
I can't change that now.
Huh?
Was this here before?
A Chinese restaurant.
It must have ramen.
Not a single customer.
But...
places like this
are often better than places
with long lines.
Okay! I'm going in.
MADAM LIN TAIPEI
Huh?
Is anyone here?
Why is it so quiet?
Excuse me!
I have a bad feeling about this.
I should leave.
Well, back to the other place.
Yes, welcome.
What?
So, someone is here.
What is this?
This strong smell of perfume?
Wow.
That's so much makeup.
Like the matron of a bar
on the outskirts of town.
No.
It's a Chinese place,
so she must be the madam.
Ramen.
Which ramen?
Shoyu ramen.
That's no way to treat a customer.
How terrible.
There's always a reason...
for a restaurant to be this empty.
I had forgotten such a basic thing.
Why did I ever enter
a restaurant like this?
Gaudy lampshades...
Chinese posters...
And the calendar...
What are those marks?
GOLF
Golf with the customers?
Seems so.
BEER / SOURS / WHISKEY
Instead of serving ramen,
this place is a bar at night.
That must be their main business.
It looks like...
I made a huge mistake.
I should have left
when no one came to take my order.
I wonder who's cooking.
Wow.
The madam is the cook?
If that's so...
I feel worse and worse.
Isn't this too fast?
I didn't wait at all.
Why did she sigh?
It's not steaming.
Oh, well.
I'm hungry. Let's eat.
It's not hot.
It's not hot at all.
What if...
the egg...
It's cold.
It's so cold that I can't taste anything.
I know it's going to taste bad
just by looking at it.
It's dry. I knew it.
Why is there so much...
wakame seaweed?
Oh no, no way.
Why is it so long?
Wakame seaweed, egg, and chashu.
I don't need any of it!
I...
hate everything in this world.
I'll...
at least eat the noodles.
Disgusting!!!
It's no good.
I can't eat anymore.
What now, the TV?
It's so loud.
So loud!
There's nothing good on.
Good.
Is she smoking?
How dare she smoke...
while a customer eats?
I can't take it anymore!
Not only was the ramen awful,
her attitude is just as bad!
I'm going to say something.
Excuse me.
It's no good.
I won't stand a chance.
What would a samurai do
in a situation like this?
Not that thinking about it helps.
I've had enough.
I'm going home.
This is awful!
I said, it's terrible.
If you don't like it, get out.
Serving such terrible food...
You think you can
get away with this?
This is my restaurant.
I can make whatever I want.
Get out.
What?
Are you drawing your sword
against a woman?!
That's right.
How can I be a man
if I don't speak up now?
Um...
Check please.
I can't be like a samurai.
Five bucks.
Huh?
I've only got a big bill.
Did she really just click her tongue?
Thanks.
Bad to the very end.
If she sees how much food I left,
will she feel sorry?
She probably won't be at all.
That Madam Devil.
Right now...
all I feel is...
defeat.
I'm back.
Cigarettes?
Does she smoke behind my back?
You scared me.
I thought you were a devil.
What?
Nothing. Don't worry about it.
Did you eat lunch?
No.
I didn't eat.
What? I would have made something
if you had called.
You have bad timing.
Sorry.
-How about instant ramen?
-Yes!
Miso or soy sauce. Take your pick.
Shoyu!
Make it the best ramen ever!
Okay.
There it is!
Here.
Thanks for the meal.
It's delicious!
Subtitle translation by
Chris Clark